[Music]
you're listening to the AI native Dev
brought to you by
Tesla hello and welcome to the Hands-On
part of this episode joining me again is
Devin Stein from Dosey and if you hadn't
seen if you hadn't listened to or seen
the previous episode we talked a bunch
about how AI can help in various cases
in including in PRS and in chatting
about issues and helping triage and
things like that as well as identifying
and looking through code bases with
varying levels of of context and we're
going to go now very Hands-On now we're
going to screen share and show a few
things that Devon's going to show us
demoing do su in the meantime we're
going to first of all look at the green
the happy golden path what happens when
a user R runs into an issue it raise an
issue there's actually an answer that's
available how can AI help us uh reduce
our time as maintainers but also help
them get to to a faster answer quicker
then what happens when actually there is
no known good answer um Can AI help us
identify what that right answer is and
then we're going to go into uh more of a
slightly bad case of what happens when
AI actually does the wrong thing and
where we can actually still improve
going forward Devon is the founder of
dosu Deon why don't you give a very
brief intro into dosu before we jump
into a screen
thanks Simon yeah so dosu for those who
don't know um is AI engineering teammate
that helps Engineers with work outside
of the IDE so trying to answer questions
triage issues for them U maintain
documentation so they can do what they
love which is code um and let dosu do
the rest uh right now dosu is very
popular within Open Source by helping
maintainers with open source maintenance
so answering questions for users and
GitHub issues and discussions triaging
issues trying to identify is it your
user error was it due to a recent change
is there a logical error in the code and
then also showing users how to
contribute so if they want to add a
feature how do they do yeah huge values
when open source maintainer I can see
why do is exponentially getting speed in
this space let's jump into a screen
share now we're talking absolute golden
path here right there's a good answer
the user doesn't know what that good
answer is it's clearly available and
dosu helps here so let's talk about the
user's workflow first so I guess
stepping back for those who have never
created an issue in open source the
status quo is you go you like running
into you're blocked on something you go
to GitHub you create an issue because
you think that it's either not possible
or you like you really need help but
unfortunately like it's very slow to
typically get a response if you create
an issue you typically the response time
is hours days weeks or months so when
you have a tool like dosu or AI
generally like the you know potential
impact for unblocking users and also
saving maintainers time because triaging
issues takes a lot of time trying to
understand where a user coming from the
the time saving is is pretty significant
here is an example like you were saying
Simon of the happy path so this is from
Apache superet where someone believes
they found a bug in PDF files and a
chart so superet is an open source tool
and they have a description like how to
reproduce it the issue they're running
into version Etc it's actually quite a
good issue when you think about GitHub
issues so dosu goes in it automatically
labels the issue helping maintainer stay
organized and then actually responds and
it's able to find that the user in this
case is actually wrong in that it's user
error and it's an expected behavior and
it shows how to implement the behavior
that the user is trying to correctly and
it does so by finding relevant code and
configuration files on the back end and
then also showing what's going on in the
front end as well and how it does the
front end also does handles sanitization
and cross- site filtering and where's it
pulling where's it pulling this kind of
data from is it is this from
documentation like public facing
documentation is it from code
documentation is it from Guides things
like that a combination so in this case
we always have the sit sources cited and
so you'll see here um that it's citing
code files in this case um but it can
also use documentation um either in the
repository or host a website um as well
as other data sources like a slack
channel for example for Community slack
and this is something that AI is is
super good at being able to take in huge
amounts of data whether it's
documentation like like you say slack
and other sources and be able to map the
kind of what someone's doing and
recognize how that differs with it the
context that it's being given is this
would you say one of the one of the
easier paths for dosu for the AI behind
dosu to actually get right most of the
time yes I would say we always try to
lean on what are llms good at and one of
the things is llms have better memories
in in a sense by being able to ingest a
ton of information index it well and
search across it you can create
something that has affect better memory
than like a maintainer so in that sense
that this is something that those who
can do well if you have forgotten about
something or don't know where something
exists or if it exists llm can be quite
exceptional at
that now in this case of course there
was good sources what that the llm could
gain access to which has the
documentation which the user could have
read initially and like identified okay
this is how I should have done this is
user error what about let's take the the
golden path to a slightly different
level where the AI that you know dosu
does really well but it's not obvious to
the user to the developer what that that
good user path is so let's say the
documentation doesn't exist that kind of
information would typically be in the
code in the maintainer head among a very
select few people how does the in that
first example it's clear how much value
AI can help because it takes the time
for the developer uh to have to respond
to these tickets or even for the tickets
to be created in the first place almost
takes all of that away how about this
second level whereby these tickets are
still going to be created and if the
information is not there how can
something like do or AI help find these
arms right I think I guess jumping to
another example here's one from jger
which is really popular tracing
framework and for of distributed
services so very complex and I think
this is a really interesting and
Powerful example of both dosu but also
AI generally where something that we got
you know me personally very excited to
start dosu is that a lot of the times
Engineers are needed is because code is
really the source of Truth for how your
product works it'll to tell you what the
edge cases are what is expected and
unexpected and here's an example where
someone is asking about timing of parent
and child spans and so this is like a
very edge case Nuance question that
there's unlikely to be documentation for
there might be but in this case there
isn't but dosu is actually able to use
in this case test information so it's
able to find relevant tests that assert
the specific behavior that the user is
asking about to give a authoritative
answer on this question so it's actually
able to find a test that says that in
this case that it's not always true that
the duration of the child spans is
contained with a parent span so it's
very specific but it's actually defined
by a test and do is able to make that
knowledge a bit more
accessible yeah absolutely this is no
one's going to troll through this this
is typically going to be maintained
about maintainer known Behavior or
whoever wrote that test kind adding that
in um it's it's almost like the tests
here are actually more the source of
Truth than the code because if you write
code and it does X Y and Z maybe
actually X and Y are intentional Z is
just something that happens and it may
be right it may be actually a bug
whereas if a test was written it's
arguably a greater chance that it's
supposed to do that unless it's stale or
or incorrectly written it's almost like
this test becomes more the source of
Truth in the code and I think it also
speaks the importance of testing
generally with when we talk about AI
software development like tests make it
much easier to reason about what the
expected behavior is those who's able to
reason about it from code but it's a lot
more authoritative and clearcut if there
is a test saying this should should be
true and if the test passed then we
believe it to be true yeah absolutely
very interesting and now let's actually
we've done the golden path what happens
when AI goes bad what happens when AI
goes wrong this is an interesting one
right if maintainers are putting that
trust and faith in in AI I guess it's
not always going to be smell of Rose is
not always going to be good let's take
us through an example of where perhaps
the suggestions or the feedback to the
user hasn't been always 100%
and these past two examples we looked at
dosu effectively saved both the user and
maintainer a ton of time user didn't
have to take through the code was
unblocked maintainer didn't have to
think about triaging the issue or
understanding the user's problem here's
a case where I think it is a common
failure point of llms and something that
dosu still struggles with where
someone's running into an issue or
looking at the open Telemetry repository
right now and they're trying to deploy
it with Helm which is tool in the
kubernetes ecosystem and they're and
it's they're running to an error and
dosu then goes in and tries to come up
with a solution it suggests something
based off looking at the code it's like
actually looking at the files and I
think you can do this and in the case
that dosu this is a correc is answer but
it's slightly misleading so you'll see
What dosu suggests is a viable
workaround so it's looking at the code
saying actually you could change it and
do this to get it to work and it's
correct but the maintainer jumps in and
explains that no actually you know the
answer is that this version the
kubernetes version the users on is not
supported and llms and dosu to a certain
extent still have a bias towards
solution know if a user has a problem
they want to be able to solve it and in
this case the answer was just no there
is no solution you're on the wrong
version essentially yeah yeah goes back
to what we were talking about in the
session as well whereby llms they they
don't want to say no right they're
always trying to find that solution and
we talked about hallucinations and
things like that whereby sometimes
they'll make up a solution other times
they'll actually find a solution but it
might might not be exactly how a
maintainer wants to present this this
component or uh might be just plain be
wrong and what's interesting about this
is I had a discussion with the
maintainer about the specific issue we
looked into the logs and if you look
into kind of the trace dosu actually
found that the right answer which was
that it's not supported but then
continued and wanted to find a solution
so even though it correctly identified
okay this user is using the wrong
version it's not supported what else
could they do it's a bit of prompting
flow engineering trying to make sure
that the if there isn't a solution like
that is sometimes is a better solution
than trying to find a workaround that
might mislead users yeah and get that
human in the loop and and and it's okay
to say no and pass things on to a human
really interesting thank you yeah again
as as was mentioned here actually Devon
this is something that can not just help
maintainers who spend a huge amount of
time doing this kind of like triage
stuff but also users who do get that
faster response that faster feedback and
turnaround time and actually get a
better experience of Open Source as a
result so it's really great that this
kind of a experience can help both sides
and make make open source more
consumable for users of both sides if
people wanted to have a play with this
what was your recommended uh path to
learn more yeah so like you're saying
dosu valuable to open source users and
maintainers but also can be used
internally at Enterprises any
engineering org you've got a lot of
questions a lot of issues that come up
dosu can help the easiest way to get
started is go to our website dos. click
on I can't remember that get Early
Access you can sign up and we have a
waiting list but we're taking people off
as quickly as we can so mention this
podcast and we'll be sure to prioritize
you amazing thank you so much Dean it's
been absolutely fascinating to see this
and I think there's a huge numbers of
people who can really benefit from this
this type of usage of AR thanks very
much Deon and everyone see you on the
next episode
[Music]
[Applause]
thanks thanks for tuning in join us next
time on the AI native Dev brought to you
by Tessa
[Music]